tiaabank.com 2016-09-05

# 

TIAA-CREF - Online Privacy Policy                                                                                                   Page 1 of 3
 Online Privacy Notice
      TIAA Direct follows the same online practices as our TIAA family of companies. The
      TIAA Online Privacy Notice is provided below.
 Click here for the FSB Customer Privacy Notice.
 Learn how TIAA-CREF is committed to keeping your personal information secure.
 Please read this notice carefully. It applies to you as a current or former customer of our products and services, or as a
 consumer interested in our products and services. We At TIAA are committed to protecting your privacy in accordance with
 the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA), as amended by the Fair and Accurate Credit Transactions Act of 2003 (FACT Act),
 the Gramm-Leach Bliley Financial Services Modernization Act (GLB), applicable state laws and this Privacy Notice. TIAA
 or the "TIAA companies" are described in this notice.
 Information We May Collect
 The nonpublic personal information we collect may include, but is not limited to, your name, address, telephone number, e-
 mail address, social security number, date of birth and your transaction and experience history with TIAA companies. We
 may use this information in connection with certain aspects of our business. For example, we may use this information to
 complete your requested transaction or to otherwise manage your relationship with the TIAA companies.
 We may obtain this information from an application or other form you have completed, from information you have chosen to
 disclose in our website, tiaa.org, or from information you have given a TIAA company in a consultation. In addition, we may
 also collect information about your creditworthiness from consumer reporting agencies, and may include your marital status,
 employment history, income, assets, credit score, credit history, open lines of credit, and the size of your household.
 If you are applying for or own a life insurance policy, we may also collect your health information. We will not disclose
 your health information to any other company, including TIAA affiliates or other persons unless authorized by you, or
 required or permitted by law or regulation.
 Cookies
 When you visit our site, we may collect information about your use of our site through "cookies". Cookies are small bits of
 information transferred to your computer's hard drive that allow us to know how often a user visits our site and the activities
 they are most interested in performing. We require the acceptance of cookies to enable users to take full advantage of
 specific services offered. We may also require you to accept cookies placed by a third party supporting this activity on our
 behalf.
 The cookies collect certain technical and navigational information only, such as computer browser type, internet protocol
 address, pages visited, and average time spent on our websites. In addition, we capture the paths taken as you move from
 page to page (i.e., your "click stream" activity). This information allows us to enhance your experience while on our site.
 Finally, we use "cookies" to establish and maintain a logged-in connection while you are in the secure section(s) of our
 website. For example, when you visit your account, perform transactions, update contact information or perform other activity
 the "cookie" allows you to navigate from page to page in a secure fashion without having to repeatedly log-in.
 Browsing to other sites:
 When you use a link to go from tiaa.org to another web site, the tiaa.org Privacy Notice is no longer in effect. Your browsing
 and interaction on any other web site is subject to the rules and policies of that site. We encourage you to read the rules and
 policies of the sites you visit to further understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information.
 How Your Information Is Used
 We use your personal information primarily to provide you with the products and services you request, and we share and
 use your personal information relating to transactions, balances, payment history and similar experiences among the TIAA
 companies to conduct their business. As permitted by law, we may also share your personal information with select partners
 with whom we have joint marketing agreements in order to provide you with a variety of products and services. We require
 these companies to meet privacy standards described below. Unless you have told us otherwise pursuant to “Your Right To
 Opt-Out” below, we may also use your personal information to market or determine your possible interest in products and
 services that the other TIAA companies offer. If you are a participant in an employer-sponsored retirement or savings plan
 investing in a TIAA or third-party annuity contract or a TIAA or third-party mutual fund, we may share the information we
 collect with your employer and its agents, if any, for plan administration purposes.
 Disclosure of Your Information
 We share your personal information with other TIAA companies as permitted by law. We will not disclose your personal
 information to anyone outside of the TIAA companies unless: 1) we have received proper consent from you;
 2) we are legally permitted to do so; or 3) we reasonably believe, in good faith, that we are legally required to do so. In order
https://www.tiaa-cref.org/public/about/inside/topics                                                                                 8/10/2015

TIAA-CREF - Online Privacy Policy                                                                                                            Page 2 of 3
 to protect the confidentiality of your personal information, including personal information that we have disclosed to a third
 party pursuant to this Privacy Notice, we take appropriate measures, including requiring each third party to execute an
 appropriate confidentiality agreement governing the use of such information and only allowing access to the information for a
 limited purpose. For example, we may provide the information to assist us with various aspects of conducting our business,
 to comply with laws or industry regulations, and/or to effectuate any contract on your behalf, including the following:
    Unaffiliated service providers (e.g., fulfillment companies and securities clearinghouses, data processing services, printers and
    mailing facilities) engaged by us;
    Unaffiliated service providers (e.g., third-party administrators) engaged by your employer;
    Unaffiliated fund and/or insurance companies and their agents whose investment options are made available to you through your
    employer-sponsored retirement or savings plan, provided monies are allocated to them on your behalf;
    Government agencies, other regulatory bodies and law enforcement officials (e.g., for tax purposes or for reporting suspicious
    transactions);
    Other organizations, with your consent or as directed by you (e.g., if you use TIAA as a financial reference in applying for credit with
    another institution); and
    Other organizations, as permitted or required by law (e.g., for fraud prevention).
 We require that third parties with which we share your personal information protect such information by utilizing the privacy
 and security safeguards required by law.
 Security of Your Information
 TIAA protects the personal information you provide against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, destruction, loss, or
 misuse. Your personal information is protected by physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards in accordance with federal
 and state standards. These safeguards include appropriate procedures for access and use of electronic data, provisions for
 the secure transmission of sensitive personal information on our website, and telephone system authentication procedures.
 Additionally, we limit access to your personal information to those TIAA employees and agents who need your personal
 information in order to offer and provide products or services to you.
 Your Right to Opt Out
 Providing us with access to your information permits us to offer you distinct advantages and better service. It enables us to
 provide you with more comprehensive financial guidance. In fact, we have established different TIAA companies to offer you
 various types of financial products and services. Sharing and using your information helps us tailor product offerings to you
 and eliminate those that may not interest you. This helps us keep expenses low.
 Federal law gives you the right to limit some but not all sharing of your personal information. You may not limit sharing of
 information of your transactions and experiences with TIAA companies, but you may limit sharing of information about your
 creditworthiness.
 Unless you tell us otherwise, (i) the TIAA company(ies) with which you have a business relationship may share information
 about your creditworthiness with other TIAA companies or (ii) other TIAA companies may use your personal information for
 marketing purposes. If you are a Vermont resident, state law gives you an additional right: we will not share information
 about your creditworthiness with other TIAA companies except with your consent.
 If you do not want the TIAA company(ies) with which you have a business relationship to share information about your
 creditworthiness with other TIAA companies or other TIAA companies to use your personal financial information for
 marketing purposes, you may simply let us know by opting out. If you opt-out, the TIAA company(ies) with
 which you have a business relationship may still notify you of their new products or services. Please note that we cannot
 withdraw any previous disclosures made with your authorization.
 To opt out of either information sharing or marketing, or both, please call the National Contact Center weekdays from 8:00 a.m.
 to 10 p.m., and on Saturday from 9 a.m. to 6 p.m, (ET) at 877-518-9161.
 You may receive more than one privacy notice from the TIAA companies depending on the products you own.
 If you own a life insurance contract, brokerage account or a TIAA-CREF Funds account with a co-owner, you and the co-
 owner may:
    opt out separately; or
    either of you may opt out for both of you.
 If you opt out separately, we will limit disclosure of information only for the owner who has opted out. If you indicate that you
 are opting out for the co-owner as well, we will limit disclosure for both of you.
 Your opt-out becomes effective as soon as practicable. It remains in effect until you revoke it in writing. No further action is
 needed. Even if you have opted out, you will receive our privacy notice each year as required by law.
 Children's Privacy Online
 This website is not directed toward children. We do not knowingly collect or post information from children under the age
 of 13.
 Changes in Our Privacy Notice
 TIAA periodically reviews its policies. We reserve the right to amend them. If we amend this Privacy Notice, we will
 continue our commitment to maintaining the security and privacy of your personal information. We will notify you of
 material changes prior to when they take effect through a banner notice in our website tiaa.org.
https://www.tiaa-cref.org/public/about/inside/topics                                                                                          8/10/2015

TIAA-CREF - Online Privacy Policy                                                                                                                                        Page 3 of 3
 How to Change or Correct Your Personal Information
 To change information such as your name, address, retirement start date, telephone number, e-mail address, or other
 personal information, please call our National Contact Center weekdays from 8:00 a.m. to 10:00 p.m., and on Saturday from
 9:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m., ET at 800-842-2252.
 You may also change your personal information by logging on to your TIAA account page at tiaa.org and submitting your
 changes. Your new information will be effective immediately. If you want to change your address on fewer than all
 contracts, or to enter a foreign address, you will need to select "click here" located under the e-mail section of the page.
 Note that certain changes cannot be processed over the phone. Address changes for payout contracts must be mailed. Also,
 to change your or your spouse's name on a contract, you must send us a letter with the following information:
    previous name with signature
    new name with signature
    Social Security Number
    Contract/account numbers
 You may send letters to:
 TIAA
 P.O. Box 1259
 Charlotte, NC 28201
 Former Customers
 If your customer relationship with TIAA ends, we will not destroy your personal information unless required or permitted
 by law. We will continue to treat your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Notice and applicable laws.
 Internet Tracking Disclosure
 We do not have the protocol that offers you the choice to opt-out of Internet tracking. You may reset your web browser
 to enable do not track functionality if your browser supports such functionality.
 The TIAA Companies
 As described in this notice, "TIAA companies” include but not limited to the following:
    Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America (TIAA) and TIAA-CREF Life Insurance Company are insurance
    companies. They provide products such as life insurance and annuities.
    College Retirement Equities Fund (CREF) is an investment company that is the companion organization to TIAA. CREF provides
    retirement annuities.
    TIAA-CREF Funds is an investment company.
    TIAA-CREF Life Funds is an investment company.
    Teachers Advisors, Inc., is an investment advisor. It provides services for our mutual funds and personal annuities.
    TIAA-CREF Investment Management, LLC, is the investment advisor to CREF.
    Teachers Personal Investors Services, Inc. (TPIS), is the principal underwriter for TIAA-CREF and Life Funds and has interest in
    tuition savings products.
    TIAA-CREF Individual & Institutional Services, LLC, is the principal underwriter for CREF and the TIAA Real Estate Account and
    is authorized by agreement to sell and service TIAA-CREF Funds, Life Funds, and interests in tuition savings products. It also
    provides brokerage accounts through TIAA Brokerage Services.
    TIAA-CREF Tuition Financing, Inc. (TFI), is an investment advisor. It provides investment management and administrative
    services for qualified tuition programs (529 Plans). TFI may receive customer information from other TIAA companies but does not
    disclose information about tuition program customers.
    TIAA-CREF Trust Company, FSB (Trust Company), is a federally chartered savings bank. It provides asset management and
    fiduciary services for individuals and institutions; acts as custodian for individual retirement accounts; and provides retail bank
    products such as checking and savings accounts, certificates of deposit and home loans under the brand of TIAA Direct. Its clients
    are subject to its own privacy notice, policies, and procedures.
    Kaspick & Company, LLC, is an investment advisor that provides advisory services to private clients, who are individuals, through
    separately managed accounts. Its clients are subject to its own privacy notice, policies, and procedures.
 February 2016
 ‡ TIAA Direct® is a division of TIAA-CREF Trust Company, FSB, Member FDIC, Equal Housing Lender                          , which provides deposit and lending products and services.
 ©2015 and prior years, Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America - College Retirement Equities Fund (TIAA-CREF), New York, NY 10017.
https://www.tiaa-cref.org/public/about/inside/topics                                                                                                                       8/10/2015
